# **Beryl Baldwin**

## LinkedIn I Portfolio

Software engineer experienced in developing and implementing adaptive solutions to complex problems at every stage of development. Exceptional at empathetic communication, idea articulation, critical thinking, and problem solving.

Clifton Strengths: Ideation, Empathy, Strategic, Relator, & Adaptability

### **DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE**

## **General Assembly**

- Completed a 12-week 500+ hour Software Engineering Immersive
- [Newt] Collaborated with a small team to create Newt, a decoupled MERN-Stack application with full CRUD functionality and API implementation that we designed to help users find a new activity to try.
- [Queue] Queue is a MEN-stack application with full CRUD functionality, API implementation, Mongoose models/MongoDB, Google OAuth, Node, and Express.js. Queue allows users to keep track of their favorite TV shows and find something new to watch.
- <u>Tic-Tac-Grow</u>] A fun take on Tic-Tac-Toe built with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and custom animations.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Founder, Product Manager

Oct. 2018 - Present

Caia | Durham, NC

- Founded a CPG FemTech startup positioned to disrupt the \$5.5 billion breast cancer diagnostics market Caia produces a tool that makes breast self exams 92% more effective than when performed with written guidelines alone.
- Executed every stage of product and business development from concept to launch/revenue generation product roadmap and vision, prototype design/development, product/market fit, website design, market research (customer interviews, customer surveys, data analysis), go-to-market strategy, and product launch.
- Exceeded revenue goals during launch by 60% with a strong go-to-market strategy and social media campaign.
- Collaborated with industry experts in oncology, women's health, materials, marketing, web development, and business management to validate and deliver the strongest possible product to the market.
- Hired, directed, and collaborated with 4 employees, including a co-founder/CTO to strengthen all elements of the product life cycle.

Personal Assistant Jan. 2015 - Jan. 2017

Private Individual | Los Angeles, CA

- Coordinated 1000+ engagements, ~75% of which required single-handedly aligning and communicating the objectives and timelines of 5+ separate teams.
- Supervised schedule, estate, staff, finances, correspondences, etc.
- Coordinated transportation, travel, wardrobe, and hair and makeup for Principal, 6 support team members.

**Executive Assistant** Oct. 2013 - Jan. 2015

Echo Lake Entertainment | Beverly Hills, CA

- Designed and created a comprehensive and interactive financial spreadsheet for 3 managers and their cumulative 112 clients, tracking client earnings, company revenue, and manager commission totaling more than \$8 million per year and increasing system efficiency by more than 65%.
- Recruited, interviewed, trained, and oversaw 15 company interns.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology, Innovation & Entrepreneurship Certificate Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp

Duke University
General Assembly

JavaScript, SQL, Angular, React, HTML, CSS, Python

#### **SKILLS & LANGUAGES**

Skills: Project & Product Management | Product Life Cycle | Product Roadmap | Organizational Strategy | Troubleshooting | User Research | Innovation | Leadership Experience | UX/UI Design | Google Analytics | Data Analysis | Agile Methodologies | Usability Testing | Javascript | CSS | HTML5 | Python | SQL | Angular | React | Node.js | Git | SQL | Python | Mongoose | MongoDB | Express

Languages: German (professional working proficiency) | French (beginner)